synthego.com 2017-12-11

# Privacy Policy - Synthetic Guide RNA for CRISPR Genome Editing | Synthego

## Synthego Corporation

Effective Date: June 15, 2017

This Privacy Policy describes the information that Synthego Corporation (“Synthego”) collects through synthego.com and its related subdomains and any other websites operated by Synthego and their related subdomains and any other websites operated by Synthego (collectively the, “Site”) and how Synthego uses it, with whom Synthego shares it, how Synthego protects it and the choices you can make about your information. The term “Site”, as used herein, refers to the above-referenced websites and their subdomains, including the content, materials, services, tools and other features and functionality we make available through such websites and their subdomains, which includes without limitation Synthego’s CRISPR Knockout Guide Designer tool. Throughout this Privacy Policy “information” includes personal information about you. Your use of this Site is subject to the Synthego Terms of Use, the Synthego Terms and Conditions of Sale, and this Privacy Policy. 

## What We Collect

In general, the types of personal information we collect include your full name, postal address, email address, postal address, telephone number, user name, password and billing information (including shipping addresses and any end-user information for the products purchased), transaction information, and credit card information. Additionally, in order to tailor our communications to you and to continuously improve our products and services, we may also ask you to voluntarily provide us with information regarding your scientific areas of interest, experience with our products, contact preferences, and other information that helps us serve you.

## How We Collect It

You provide us your personal information when you (a) register on this Site or with our Customer Service team; (b) place orders with us online, via phone, fax, or other electronic methods; (c) participate in trade shows; (d) interact with our sales and marketing teams; or (e) otherwise provide us with or make available your personal information through other registration and data capturing processes, including other public sources of such data.

In general, when you visit Synthego at the Site, when you interact with us in other ways, or you otherwise voluntarily provide us with information, you can choose how much information you share. You can refuse to supply personal information, with the caveat that it may prevent you from engaging in certain website-related activities.

We may automatically collect other information about you, including web browser type, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, domain name of your Internet service provider, your geographic location, the Site pages that you visit and the time of your visits, and aggregated information that cannot be used to specifically identify you when you use or visit this Site.

We also may collect information about you from publicly available sources.

We may combine any of the information we collect from or about you and use it in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

Additionally, third parties, or affiliates owned by Synthego, may provide information to us about you, and if and to the extent they do, we will treat such combined information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## How We Use It

Synthego uses your information to better understand your needs and to provide you with better service. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction, to communicate with you (when you have not expressed an interest otherwise), to update you on services and benefits, to improve this Site, to personalize features and other services for you, to conduct market and research analysis.

The purposes for which you provided it;

To process and respond to your inquiries and comments;  
To send you information about your relationship or transactions with us;  
To develop new products and services;  
To identify you as a user of this Site;  
To allow you to participate in surveys;  
To contact you with information, including promotional information, that we believe will be of interest to you, done either by us or a third party;  
To create anonymous data, which we may use for any purpose;  
To compile aggregate data for internal and external business purposes;  
To analyze this Site;  
To send emails;  
To generate and review reports and data about our user base and service usage patterns;  
To analyze the accuracy, effectiveness, usability or popularity of this Site;  
To prevent fraudulent transactions, monitor against theft and otherwise protect our users and our business;  
To administer and troubleshoot this Site;  
And as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy and the Synthego Terms of Use and the Synthego Terms and Conditions of Sale.

## With Whom We Share Your Personal Information

Information may be disclosed to third parties in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

We provide access to your personal information to our affiliates, agents, vendors or service providers, who help us to provide products or services to you, or otherwise perform functions on our behalf and in accordance with this Privacy Policy regarding our affiliates and with our agreements regarding our agents, vendors or service providers.

If we become involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, we may share or transfer your information to a third party or parties in connection therewith.

To the extent permitted by applicable law, we may disclose information about you to third parties to enforce or apply the Synthego Terms of Use or the Synthego Terms and Conditions of Sale; comply with law, in response to subpoenas, warrants, or court orders, or in connection with any legal process or cooperate with government or law enforcement officials or private parties, including laws outside of your country of residence, protect our rights, reputation, safety and property, or that of our users or others, protect against legal liability; establish or exercise our rights to defend against legal claims; or to investigate, prevent or take action regarding suspected illegal activities, suspected fraud, the rights, reputation, safety or property of us, users or others, violation of the Synthego Terms of Use or the Synthego Terms and Conditions of Sale, our policies or agreements or as otherwise required by law.

We may share aggregated anonymous information relating to visitors to and users of this Site with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties.

Please see Cookies and Other Tools; Do Not Track below.

## Cookies and Other Tools; Do Not Track

Like many websites, Synthego uses cookies, web beacons, tracking pixels, and other technologies (collectively, “Tools”) to improve your Site experience. A cookie is a file containing text that is placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites. With cookies in place, our system will recognize you whenever you use your web browser (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox) to connect to our page. This enables us to present you with custom web pages and otherwise improve your user experience.

Disabling cookies may prevent you from using certain features of the Site such as registering or placing orders. If you choose not to take advantage of these interactive features, you can set up your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie has been sent. The “Help” section of your browser will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting cookies. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage or delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Third parties may collect personally identifiable information about an individual user’s online activities over time and across different Internet services when a user uses this Site.

Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that users can set in their web browsers. When a user turns on DNT, the browser sends a message to websites requesting that they don’t track the user. For more information about DNT, see [http://donottrack.us](http://donottrack.us/). At this time, we do not respond to DNT signals sent from web browsers or other mechanisms that provide users the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of personally identifiable information about a user’s online activities over time and across third party websites or Internet services.

## Transfer of Data to Other Countries

Any information you provide to Synthego may be stored and processed, transferred between and accessed from the United States and other countries, which may not guarantee the same level of protection of personal information as the one in which you reside. However, Synthego will handle your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, regardless of where your personal information is stored.

## Other Websites

This Privacy Policy applies only to this Site. This Site may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave this Site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such websites and such websites are not governed by this Privacy Policy. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy policy applicable to the website in question.

## Security

We use administrative, physical and technical measures to safeguard your personal information and help protect it from unauthorized access. All of our website communications are HTTPS based, and provide end to end encryption for any data flowing between Synthego and the browser. We also use both passwords and user names to authenticate users (i.e. to verify the identity of each registered user). Users are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of their own passwords.

However, no security can be 100% effective, so we cannot guarantee the security of your information. No Internet or email transmission is ever fully secure or error free. Email or other communications sent through this Site may not be secure. You should use caution whenever submitting information through this Site and take special care in deciding which information you provide us with. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us by contacting us at [info@synthego.com](mailto:info@synthego.com).

## Opting Out

If you do not wish to receive certain communications from us, you may opt out by (1) declining the service offered when registering or at other information gathering points on this Site, or (2) informing us that you no longer wish to receive such communications by emailing us at [info@synthego.com](mailto:info@synthego.com), unless such communications from us are required by law or contract or do not require your consent under applicable laws. If you opt out of certain communications, you may not be able to access certain of our products or services.

Please see Cookies and Other Tools; Do Not Track above.

## Children’s Privacy

We do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, please do not submit any personal information through this Site.  If you have reason to believe that we may have accidentally received personal information from an individual under age 18, please contact us immediately at [info@synthego.com](mailto:info@synthego.com).

## Access and Correction of Information

You may at any time request access to a summary of your personal information held by us, and request corrections or updates to that information. We will make reasonable efforts to respond promptly to such requests for information in accordance with local laws. Our response to such requests will be limited to information under our direct control.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible at info@synthego.com. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may update or modify and post revisions to this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. This Privacy Policy was made effective on the date indicated above.

## Contact Details

If you have any questions or concerns about his policy, please contact Synthego at [info@synthego.com](mailto:info@synthego.com).
